<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clove on Beet Life</title>
    <link>https://beet.life/ingredients/clove/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clove on Beet Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 14:51:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://beet.life/ingredients/clove/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Garam Masala?</title>
      <link>https://beet.life/articles/what-is-garam-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 14:51:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beet.life/articles/what-is-garam-masala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Garam masala is a ground spice blend used in South Asian and Southeast
Asian dishes. The spices used vary depending on the region and many have adopted their own versions.
The common spices used are cardamon, clove, cumin, cinnamon, coriander, peppercorn, and nutmeg.
Some add fennel seed, nigella seeds, dry mango, mace, anistar, different types of chili and even
mustard seeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uses:&lt;/strong&gt; It can be used in stews, soups, marinades, salad dressings, as a rub, in boiled rice
and even in desserts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storage:&lt;/strong&gt; Using a tin can with double lids is the best way to keep ground spices fresh. We use
tea tin metal containers for our spices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The garam masala spice we use is store bought. It has coriander, red chili, cumin, clove, anistar, mace, fennel, black pepper, bay leaves, cinnamon, dry mango, salt and clove leaves. However, you can also make your own spice blend by using the common spices mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Recipe&#34;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&#34;bl-how-to-instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol itemprop=&#34;recipeInstructions&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ItemList&#34; itemprop=&#34;itemListOrder&#34; content=&#34;http://schema.org/ItemListOrderAscending&#34; class=&#34;bl-recipe-steps&#34;&gt;

&lt;li itemprop=&#34;itemListElement&#34; class=&#34;bl-recipe-steps__step&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roast equal parts of each spice except for nutmeg and clove in a dry skillet on medium heat.
Use &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; parts of nutmeg and clove. If you want to add some heat, add cayenne, dried ginger or
red pepper flakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li itemprop=&#34;itemListElement&#34; class=&#34;bl-recipe-steps__step&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;After roasting for about 3 minutes, grind them in a spice grinder. Let it cool and store in a
sealable tin can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;


&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Try making our &lt;a href=&#34;https://beet.life/recipes/garam-masala-spiced-lentil/&#34;&gt;Garam Masala Spiced Red Lentil&lt;/a&gt; recipe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt; - This is not a sponsored post. We are not affiliated with any products or brands shown or mentioned in this post and we did not receive any compensation for writing this post at the time of writing.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>