<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communication Skills on Beet Life</title>
    <link>https://beet.life/tags/communication-skills/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communication Skills on Beet Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 10:11:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://beet.life/tags/communication-skills/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Effective Strategies For Resolving Disputes</title>
      <link>https://beet.life/articles/strategies-for-mediating-disputes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 10:11:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beet.life/articles/strategies-for-mediating-disputes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-ask-open-ended-questions&#34;&gt;1. Ask open-ended questions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to ask open-ended questions in order to identify the other person&amp;rsquo;s position and interest. Open-ended questions invite a narrative and paints a more accurate picture of what the problem is. For example,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You SHOULD NOT say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nohighlight&#34;&gt;Do you regret your decision?
Do you want to compromise?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You SHOULD say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nohighlight&#34;&gt;How do you feel about your decision? (open-ended)

If I am willing to do [...],
what are you willing to do? (open-ended)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-focus-on-the-problem&#34;&gt;2. Focus on the problem.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose there is a dispute between over uncleaned dog poop in one neighbor&amp;rsquo;s lawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nohighlight&#34;&gt;Neighbor: This is not the first time your dog
made my life difficult! He also bit my
daughter last summer! That dog has to go!

You: Your daughter threw a rock at my dog!

Neighbor: That&#39;s a lie!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a heated conversation, it is highly likely that the conversation can get out of topic. In these situations, you should remind the parties in conflict or the person you are in conflict with to focus on particular issues. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nohighlight&#34;&gt;Your claim that my dog bit your daughter
last summer is a separate matter.
Let&#39;s focus on the poop problem first.
What do you want to do to resolve the
uncleaned dog poop?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-reframe-the-issue-and-praphrase-the-language&#34;&gt;3. Reframe the issue and praphrase the language.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paraphrasing inflamatory language and/or reframing the issue helps people focus on the problem at hand. For example,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nohighlight&#34;&gt;Neighbor: You lazy [expletive]! You don&#39;t care about other people!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response, YOU SHOULD NOT SAY:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nohighlight&#34;&gt;So the issue for you is that [his/my] dog pooped on
your lawn and [he/I] didn&#39;t clean it up?&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YOU SHOULD SAY:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nohighlight&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;If I understand correctly, the issue for you is
that [a] dog pooped in your lawn,
but [no one] cleaned it up. Is this correct?&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice how using neutral language reframes the issue and moves towards a solution rather than more conflict. Another example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nohighlight&#34;&gt;Husband: You do not give me enough money!
Wife: Do I hear you correctly when you say you would
like me to increase my financial contribution to the household?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-react-positively&#34;&gt;4. React positively.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People involved in a dispute are generally frustrated or angry. It is highly likely that they will take that frustration or anger out on you. It is important for you not to take things personally and react positively. For example,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nohighlight&#34;&gt;Aggrieved Person: You think I&#39;m lying!
You&#39;re on his side!

You: What makes you think that?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Providing a calm non-defensive invitation for the aggrieved person to explain their position or how they feel about the situation provides you with an understanding of what their interests are and how to best resolve the issue at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-facilitate-an-interest-based-conversation-by-providing-reality-checks&#34;&gt;5. Facilitate an interest-based conversation by providing reality checks.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Providing a reality check may facilitate a solution when a person is unwilling to move from his/her position. Whenever a person threatens or demands for something unrealistic, replying with a challenge will create more animosity between you and the other person. For example,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nohighlight&#34;&gt;Person: I will sue you in court!
You: Go ahead!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, use open-ended questions that force the other person to reexamine the feasibility of their demands or threats. It also opens up a discussion about more reasonable options. For example,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nohighlight&#34;&gt;How will suing me stop dogs from pooping in your lawn?

How will suing me clean up the poop in your lawn?

How is the court going to enforce what you are proposing?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like using mnemonics to remember certain concepts. Next time you encounter conflict, remember to &lt;strong&gt;OFRRR&lt;/strong&gt; love! (1) open-ended question, (2) focus on the problem, (3) Reframe and paraphrase, (4) React positively, (5) Reality check!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt; - This is not a sponsored post. We are not affiliated with any products or brands shown or mentioned in this post and we did not receive any compensation for writing this post at the time of writing.&lt;/em&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Simple Rules When Resolving Or Dealing With Conflicts</title>
      <link>https://beet.life/articles/three-simple-rules-when-resolving-or-dealing-with-conflicts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 09:37:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beet.life/articles/three-simple-rules-when-resolving-or-dealing-with-conflicts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Conflicts arise when a person&amp;rsquo;s needs are not met and is often triggered by fear, sense of unfairness, and difference in opinions, values or attitudes. People quarrel over chores, finances, timelines, territory, etc. You name it, people have fought about it. Here are three simple rules to keep in mind when resolving or dealing with a conflict:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-the-fair-solution-is-not-always-the-best-solution-a-good-solution-to-a-problem-is-one-that-addresses-the-concerns-and-needs-of-each-party-in-conflict&#34;&gt;1. The &amp;lsquo;fair&amp;rsquo; solution is not always the best solution. A good solution to a problem is one that addresses the concerns and needs of each party in conflict.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of dividing fault or splitting the difference equally as the fairest way of resolving a conflict is flawed because opposing parties usually do not want the same things even though they say they do. Consider this example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two daughters are fighting over the last lemon in the kitchen. Each say they want the lemon. They bicker for ten minutes and don&amp;rsquo;t listen to each other. The mother says, &amp;ldquo;split the lemon.&amp;rdquo; Both daughters do not want to split the lemon. The bickering goes on. The mother forces them to split the lemon in half. Both daughters walk away unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without addressing each of her daughter&amp;rsquo;s concerns, the mother failed to realize that one daughter wanted to make lemonade and the other needed the lemon zest of a whole lemon to cook her favorite dish. Although both said they wanted the whole lemon, their needs differed. With this new information, it is clear that the best solution is to give one daughter lemon juice and the other lemon zest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-the-more-effective-way-of-solving-a-dispute-is-to-listen-carefully-to-each-person-and-use-the-information-they-give-you-to-address-their-needs&#34;&gt;2. The more effective way of solving a dispute is to listen carefully to each person and use the information they give you to address their needs.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, in a heated conversation, each party&amp;rsquo;s needs and wants will not be easily apparent. Deescalate the situation by making the speaker feel understood. Ask questions like &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;In my understanding, you said you want [&amp;hellip;] Is this correct?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. A question like this is useful because it reiterates what the speaker is saying and asking the speaker to reaffirm whether or not you understood him/her correctly. Not only does it deescalate a heated situation, it gives the speaker a chance to think about his/her needs by affirming or negating what you said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-mind-your-language-state-your-wants-and-needs-avoid-talking-in-absolutes&#34;&gt;3. Mind your language! State your wants and needs. Avoid talking in absolutes.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only siths deal with absolutes. Don&amp;rsquo;t use sentences like these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;You never take the trash out.&amp;quot;
&amp;quot;You always forget to pick up the kids from school.&amp;quot;
&amp;quot;You always fail to meet the deadline.&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You + Absolute + Action&lt;/strong&gt; conveys blame rather than cooperation. It escalates an already heated conversation. It may feel like the person &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; did what you asked or &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; failed to do what you wanted, but it won&amp;rsquo;t do you any good to verbalize that. You won&amp;rsquo;t get what you want if you speak in absolutes because it invites defensive action rather than cooperation. It steers the conversation away from the solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I + need/want + person to do [&amp;hellip;]&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; instead. This is more effective because it conveys cooperation and invites action rather than a defensive act/reaction. For example,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;I want you to take the trash out every week.&amp;quot;
&amp;quot;I need you to be consistent when picking the kids up from school.&amp;quot;
&amp;quot;I want to know ahead of time if you are having a hard time meeting the deadline.&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you state your wants and needs, you are opening up a conversation and letting the other person know clearly what you want them to do. There is no shaming or blaming involved; therefore, the other person is more receptive to coming up with a solution to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt; - This is not a sponsored post. We are not affiliated with any products or brands shown or mentioned in this post and we did not receive any compensation for writing this post at the time of writing.&lt;/em&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>